<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hofeiying.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://hofeiying.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-27T15:25:25+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Home</title><subtitle>Product Leader.</subtitle><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">YOU’RE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR HOW OTHER’S FEEL</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/You-are-not-responsible-for-how-others-feel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="YOU’RE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR HOW OTHER’S FEEL" /><published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/You-are-not-responsible-for-how-others-feel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/You-are-not-responsible-for-how-others-feel/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve always been someone who’s emotionally intelligent, an empath who’s constantly at war with her own thoughts. I can’t help but have this gnawing feeling that I’m always responsible for how others feel.</p>

<p>It’s extremely heavy and exhausting. I can’t remember when I started developing this but carrying the emotional weight of everyone around me became a reflex, almost like muscle memory. For years, I can’t help but always scan the room for any discomfort. It’s like a natural gift for attracting tension, I genuinely cannot control it. I would read between the lines of someone’s tone and immediately jump into “I need to fix this” mode. Sometimes, I’d twist myself into knots trying to prevent someone else’s sadness, frustration, or anger…Even when I had nothing to do with it. In some cases, my anxious effort to make others feel better can lead to misunderstandings when I say or do the wrong things. It’s pretty ironic.</p>

<p>But here’s what I’m learning: feeling responsible for others’ emotions just means that I may be more compassionate than others. But, at the same time, iit makes me hostage to people’s moods. And worse, it deprives them of the space to feel what they need to feel, process it, and grow.</p>

<p>Other people are allowed to be upset. They’re allowed to be disappointed, frustrated, and even mad. But it doesn’t mean I caused it. And even if I did unintentionally, it doesn’t mean I’m obligated to fix it immediately. I’ve been through those feelings myself and I never had the expectation that others should fix it for me.</p>

<p>Boundaries are not walls; they are clarity. They remind me where I should draw the line and where others do too. I can care deeply without carrying the whole load on my shoulders all the time. I can be supportive without self-abandoning. It is not my duty to be a saint and try to fix things. I need to start paying more attention to myself, not towards others.</p>

<p>So if you’re like me, an empath who’s always bracing for emotional impact, maybe this is your reminder too: you’re not responsible for how others feel. You’re only responsible for showing up when things get hard for them. That’s enough, and that’s always been enough.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve always been someone who’s emotionally intelligent, an empath who’s constantly at war with her own thoughts. I can’t help but have this gnawing feeling that I’m always responsible for how others feel.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Journaling Platform</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/A-Journaling-Platform/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Journaling Platform" /><published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/A-Journaling-Platform</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/A-Journaling-Platform/"><![CDATA[<p>I want to build a journaling platform that helps people with emotional wellness and connection. But why a journaling platform?</p>

<p>From an early age, I always knew I was different from everyone else. I was consciously aware of my own thoughts and feelings. I was not like other kids who had ambitions of being doctors, lawyers or astronauts. At that time I didn’t know there was a name for it, an entrepreneur. But I always thought of creating something that would make an impactful change in our world.</p>

<p>Growing up in a toxic environment didn’t go exactly well with my ambitions. I suffered tremendously from the psychological abuse and my perception about my own abilities deteriorated. I’d wasted time battling mental health issues and fighting addictions when I should’ve been focusing on my dreams.</p>

<p>Then one day, came a benefactor. He knew of my struggles and asked if I’d thought of creating a product around my story. At that moment, everything clicked. My whole life has been centred around watching others and myself struggle with mental health. Yet, with a burning passion to create change, it had never occurred to me that I should build something to fix the problem. A problem that I resonate with and others who were like myself.</p>

<p>I’ve always been reserved about my feelings. I never felt like burdening others with my emotional baggage. So I turned to journaling. It started with a diary when I was 9 and moved to a notes application on my phone. Allowing myself to write about my feelings helped me re-organise them and understand myself better. It was my safe space.</p>

<p>Eventually came the dark age of social media. None were tailored specifically to host a large body of text for journaling. Those were created for people to look glamorous. People only showed you what they wanted you to see. Most people end up developing mental health issues and feel trapped because a judgement-free system has yet to exist. Society started creating unrealistic expectations on just about everything. From the way you look, to the lifestyle you’re living, even to who you’re dating. That itself is enough to create the pressure to be a perfect being. And it made people forget that we’re only human. To be human, is to feel.</p>

<p>Reddit is a good example for people using anonymous profiles to share their feelings in various communities. Most leverage it to vent their thoughts and seek advice or validation from strangers. I myself have turned to Reddit to seek comfort from others who faced similar situations. Some stories have positively impacted me as mine have done for others. It’s the feeling of receiving emotional support and building connections out of your best or worst situations from strangers. It’s the ability to feel seen in a sea of strangers and understanding that you’re not alone. It’s a good system, but people still don’t feel safe. It’s evident because many users begin their post with “I’m using a throw-away account”. This signifies that users don’t feel comfortable enough.</p>

<p>Society has made it sound abnormal to feel a certain way. Reddit simply isn’t built for mental health wellness albeit its anonymity features. Everyone uses it as a journal because they know it’s where everyone else dumps their emotional feelings too. We need a platform that advocates for mental health. To normalize having struggles and help people realise that we are only human. Our feelings matter more than we think and we deserve a safe space to talk about it.</p>

<p>My vision for this journaling platform is to create a safe digital space for people to emotionally connect through journaling. Journaling our thoughts would reveal an unfiltered and raw version of ourselves. Through reading what others might be feeling, it heals the societal belief that everyone is flawless. With our world being digitized today and advancements in technology, this platform can revolutionise the way mental health is being viewed or treated.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I want to build a journaling platform that helps people with emotional wellness and connection. But why a journaling platform?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Love In The Dark</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/Love-In-The-Dark/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Love In The Dark" /><published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/Love-In-The-Dark</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/Love-In-The-Dark/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s 12:03 AM and sleep evades me. My mind churns with anxieties, tangled in thoughts of overdue bills and mounting debts. Each notification of an unpaid bill feels like a heavy weight, pushing me into a corner of vulnerability I’ve never known before. The fear of being unable to meet even basic needs is unsettling and humbling.</p>

<p>Yet, within this unsettling chaos, clarity begins to surface. I am finally seeing the consequences of my actions and the choices I made without fully understanding its severity. Despite the turmoil and suffering I experienced, it feels as though this difficult chapter is shaping me, and the beginning to something better.</p>

<p>For too long, I’ve been trapped in a cycle of self-doubt and negativity. Accepting that I could be loved seemed like an impossible feat, something that’s perhaps reserved exclusively for some others. Maybe these feelings took root the day my father made me feel a sense of abandonment, imprinting a deep sense of void in my soul. But there comes a moment when I must choose to let go of these childhood trauma and step forward. At some point, blaming my predicament on past memories becomes nothing short of an excuse to behave the way I do. It’s excruciatingly exhausting to carry such old pain around every day when all I need to do is simply let go and move on.</p>

<p>It feels as though I’m standing at the lowest point of my life, yet strangely, hope accompanies me through this darkness. Perhaps this is precisely what I needed to experience in order to change. Unexpectedly, it’s in this moment of hopelessness that I’ve come to see that I am deeply loved. Friends have provided unconditional genuine care, stepping up in ways I never expected. My family offers support that feels like an embrace, comforting and reassuring in its sincerity. Reflecting on these moments fills me with immeasurable gratitude and hope that I had forgotten existed.</p>

<p>As I write these words from my bed tonight, those haunting thoughts of despair have begun to slowly fade. I realize that my long-held beliefs about being unloved were unfounded fears rooted in past trauma. No one explicitly told me I didn’t deserve love. I told myself that because I feared rejection. I feared abandonment again. This difficult journey has taught me that love and support surround me, if only I choose to see and accept it. If it takes pain and suffering to acknowledge the fact that I’m loved, I would gladly go through this predicament over and over again. Because that’s the price I’m willing to pay to be let loose from the chains that withheld me from acknowledging love.</p>

<p>All it takes is opening our hearts to the love already present in our lives. It won’t be easy but it will come. We all deserve kindness, compassion, and genuine connections, no matter how deep our struggles might be. Self-hatred is the enemy of joy. We all deserve to love and be loved, don’t forget that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s 12:03 AM and sleep evades me. My mind churns with anxieties, tangled in thoughts of overdue bills and mounting debts. Each notification of an unpaid bill feels like a heavy weight, pushing me into a corner of vulnerability I’ve never known before. The fear of being unable to meet even basic needs is unsettling and humbling.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Truth Will Set You Free</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/The-Truth-Will-Set-You-Free/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Truth Will Set You Free" /><published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/The-Truth-Will-Set-You-Free</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/The-Truth-Will-Set-You-Free/"><![CDATA[<p>The value of honesty was instilled in me throughout childhood, not just at home but also in classrooms and by figures of authority. Growing up, it was common to hear elders stress the importance of truthfulness. However, honesty wasn’t always simple.</p>

<p>My father was intimidating, and even now, memories of his anger unsettle me. Despite this fear, as a child, I often found myself in trouble. Teachers would call home to report my misbehavior, and inevitably, my father would be waiting, cane in hand. He would stare deeply into my eyes, asking if the accusations were true. Fearful, I’d shake my head, nervously stuttering, “No.”</p>

<p>Even when I thought I’d delivered my most convincing lie, he saw right through it. Each time he caught me lying, he would say firmly, “I hate it when you lie. Look at me and tell me the truth, or you’ll face the consequence.”</p>

<p>So, I adapted. I started telling the truth, believing honesty would grant me leniency. But I was mistaken. Even when truthful, particularly when wrongly accused or misunderstood, I faced punishment just as severe. This harsh reality taught me a painful lesson: honesty doesn’t always protect you from criticism or consequence.</p>

<p>The abusive repercussions of lying to my father had a profound impact. Because he always saw through my deceit, I became convinced that I was simply born to be terrible at lying. Subconsciously, this belief lingered, making lying extraordinarily difficult for me when growing up. Ironically, as I grew older, the fear of hurting others became greater than the fear of getting caught in a lie. Lying eventually became less frightening than allowing those I loved to see the truth about me.</p>

<p>Whenever confronted with admitting my truth, I felt compelled to bend the truth or outright lie. My dishonesty never arose from malicious intent, nor was it ever employed to harm others. Instead, my lies were always about concealing my own wrongdoings. It was always done to protect myself and others. I’d rather carry my burdens alone, despite the mental toll, believing I was sparing those I love from disappointment and shame at discovering just how flawed I truly am.</p>

<p>Each lie told became increasingly harder to manage, for lies inevitably require more lies to sustain them. Over time it gets harder and harder to catch up with them because they’re always made up on the spur of the moment when panic sets in.</p>

<p>“No man has a good enough memory to be a good liar.”</p>

<p>The guilt from lying and the shame of feeling like you’ve failed everyone, including yourself, gnaws at you relentlessly. The constant dread that your lies coming to light is exhausting, like dragging a heavy weight you cannot release till the truth is finally told.</p>

<p>Being self-aware amplifies the agony of lying; the strain on your conscience is immense. Sometimes I wish I was oblivious to the discomfort of deceit. Maybe I wouldn’t be constantly haunted by the guilt that follows.</p>

<p>Lying, in those moments, always felt like a non-negotiable option. You craft false narratives, construct versions of yourself you wish were true. If you must be judged for your mistakes, you prefer it to be perceived as something “less” severe than the reality, because in those brief moments, lying offers temporary relief and makes you feel better. Even though you know it’s wrong..</p>

<p>But here’s an undeniable truth: Lies always surface eventually. And when they do, the erosion of trust cuts deeper than any temporary discomfort honesty might have caused initially. Consider the scenario where your truth might cause no immediate harm to your loved ones, but being caught in a lie or multiple lies later would inflict deeper pain. It creates a barrier for trust. I’ve always known this from the moment I learnt to bury uncomfortable truths. Despite that, whenever I faced such situations, I still instinctively believe that my lies are acts of mercy on myself and the people who I love. Unfortunately, It’s a delusion that only the insecure would buy.</p>

<p>Having said so much, I doubt I was able to encapsulate the true complexity and emotional toll of lying. But one thing is certain: the truth, however painful, will set you free, even if it feels utterly unbearable in the moment. Telling the truth is also a form of acceptance and a sign that you are ready for growth. Am I Ready?</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The value of honesty was instilled in me throughout childhood, not just at home but also in classrooms and by figures of authority. Growing up, it was common to hear elders stress the importance of truthfulness. However, honesty wasn’t always simple.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Mirage of Greener Grass</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/The-Mirage-of-Greener-Grass/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Mirage of Greener Grass" /><published>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/The-Mirage-of-Greener-Grass</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/The-Mirage-of-Greener-Grass/"><![CDATA[<p>I grew up under the shadow of an abusive and controlling father. My childhood felt like being a bird trapped in a cage, constantly yearning for the sky that was always just beyond my reach. Every daydream revolved around the moment I’d finally gather the courage to break free from his grip and experience life on my own terms. I genuinely believed that freedom was the missing piece, the ultimate goal that would finally make life complete. For that freedom, I was willing to pay any price.</p>

<p>Eventually, I found the strength to reclaim my life. I took the leap and fought hard for the freedom I’d longed for. Yet, to my dismay, happiness eluded me. Over the years, the stress and emotional turmoil led me to gain 20 kilograms, as I resorted to binge eating to cope. The weight gain amplified my insecurities, fueling self-loathing and sadness. It might seem trivial to some, but the agony of body dysmorphia is something only those who’ve experienced it, can truly grasp. Again, I convinced myself: if only I could achieve an athlete’s physique, then surely contentment would follow, even if it meant sacrificing some of that hard-earned freedom.</p>

<p>And so, determined, I pushed forward, disciplined myself, and successfully got into shape. Finally, I had both the freedom and the physique others admired. But even then, true peace remained elusive. University began, and with it came overwhelming anxiety about the uncertainty of my future. To escape this anxiety, I fell into another trap,addiction, which quickly led to mounting debt. Life felt like an endless cycle of misery, pulling me back into the same trap. I thought again: if only I were debt-free, then surely I’d find happiness.</p>

<p>But here’s the truth I’ve come to painfully realize: the grass always appears greener until it isn’t. Even if my debt vanished overnight at the cost of my freedom or my health, dissatisfaction would inevitably linger. Real happiness doesn’t spring from external circumstances or the resolution of temporary hardships. True contentment must be cultivated deep within ourselves, nurtured through gratitude and a sincere appreciation for life’s small yet meaningful milestones. Constantly chasing after more only leaves us perpetually empty.</p>

<p>Greed, after all, is a sin,not merely because it makes us endlessly desire more, but because it blinds us to the beauty and abundance we already possess.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I grew up under the shadow of an abusive and controlling father. My childhood felt like being a bird trapped in a cage, constantly yearning for the sky that was always just beyond my reach. Every daydream revolved around the moment I’d finally gather the courage to break free from his grip and experience life on my own terms. I genuinely believed that freedom was the missing piece, the ultimate goal that would finally make life complete. For that freedom, I was willing to pay any price.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Life Spent On Self-Sabotage</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/A-Life-Spent-On-Self-Sabotage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Life Spent On Self-Sabotage" /><published>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/A-Life-Spent-On-Self-Sabotage</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/A-Life-Spent-On-Self-Sabotage/"><![CDATA[<p>I always assumed that the older I got, the closer I’d be to the peace I desperately yearned for as a child. The truth is, peace was never something I could reliably expect. Conflict felt more certain than winning the lottery. If you asked me to name a moment from my childhood when I genuinely felt safe or at ease, I’m not sure I could. Each time I dared to catch my breath, another storm was already brewing on the horizon.</p>

<p>At some point, I stopped believing I deserve a simple, peaceful life. My childhood memories became filled with endless loops of tension and turmoil. There was always a feeling of judgment day looming, a heavy, unsettling sensation that prevented me from ever truly feeling like I don’t constantly have weights on my shoulders.</p>

<p>These experiences, imprinted so early, eventually turned peace itself into something frightening, even dangerous. When calm arrived, I’d instinctively brace myself for disaster. Silence didn’t soothe me; it triggered anxiety. Instead of savoring these tranquil moments, I spent them anticipating their inevitable demise. This anxiety was so profound that I couldn’t allow myself to trust in moments of genuine calm. How could I if all I’ve ever known was chaos?</p>

<p>And so began my habit of self-sabotage—a quiet war against my own happiness. I subconsciously learned to disrupt the peace by myself before something else could destroy it. Over time, my body and mind developed an involuntary reflex to push away tranquility. Happiness felt too vulnerable, too uncertain, and too good to be real. Sabotaging myself became my way of maintaining control; if the chaos was self-inflicted, at least it was predictable.</p>

<p>These acts of self-sabotage have inflicted tremendous pains on my healing. It doesn’t help being so aware of myself yet having no way to prevent these habits from reoccurring.  But I want it to stop. I need it to stop.</p>

<p>Looking back clearly at the patterns I’ve carried with me, I’ve begun to wonder if perhaps the bravest thing I could do is to stop fighting against myself. Maybe the real challenge isn’t surviving chaos, but allowing myself the bravery of embracing calm without conditions or skepticism. Perhaps the most powerful rebellion against a painful past isn’t more struggle, but learning how to rest in moments of genuine ease without fearing their end.</p>

<p>I’m slowly realizing that peace doesn’t have to be a fragile, nor a temporary gift; it’s not something reserved for those who’ve earned it through endless suffering. Peace is steady, patient, and always available beneath life’s turbulence, just like a river gently flowing, ready for me to finally trust it enough to let myself drift along its current, without constantly looking ahead for rapids. If I learn to simply embrace the imperfections of life by just being at peace, there wouldn’t be a need for self-sabotage.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I always assumed that the older I got, the closer I’d be to the peace I desperately yearned for as a child. The truth is, peace was never something I could reliably expect. Conflict felt more certain than winning the lottery. If you asked me to name a moment from my childhood when I genuinely felt safe or at ease, I’m not sure I could. Each time I dared to catch my breath, another storm was already brewing on the horizon.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Edge of Grief</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/The-Edge-of-Grief/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Edge of Grief" /><published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/The-Edge-of-Grief</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/The-Edge-of-Grief/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve always been an emotional person. Someone who’s deeply sentimental, easily moved by small gestures, old photos, and fading memories. Thankfully, I never had to face real loss when I was young. But as I grow older, the thought of grief feels like a shadow that creeps closer with each passing year.</p>

<p>There have been moments where I’ve spiraled into panic attacks, triggered by obsessive thoughts of losing the people I love. These imagined tragedies loop in my mind like a broken record. I know they’re not real, but when they take over, logic disappears. I begin to grieve events that haven’t happened. It feels real and I grieve for a situation that doesn’t exist. And the fear becomes overwhelming: What if one day someone I love is just… gone? How would I survive that?</p>

<p>Not long ago, someone close to me passed away. A friend, but more than that, a steady older brother presence in my life. Someone who looked out for me when I didn’t know I needed looking after. His death came without warning, so sudden and sharp. It cracked something open in me, forcing questions I had been avoiding to surface again.</p>

<p>What is this life? What does it mean to be here, only to vanish? Why does everything feel so temporary, so brittle, so easily lost?</p>

<p>If I could choose my fate, I think I’d rather leave this world before my loved ones. It might sound selfish, but I’d rather be spared the pain of loss than endure the silence that follows it. The truth is harsh: when someone dies, they’re truly gone. People say memories live on, but even they will begin to blur someday. Eventually, the voice you once heard clearly becomes an echo. Photos become symbols. You see, death steals more than just people, it steals the feeling of them.</p>

<p>Everything in life is ephemeral. It is fragile. It can change overnight.</p>

<p>And maybe the only way to cope with this inevitable truth is to stay grounded in the present. To fully appreciate the people I love while they are still here. To be more intentional with my time. More generous with my love. More present in my conversations. I have begun taking more photos, capturing the ordinary, a shared laugh, a quiet meal, a hand held a little longer, because I fear forgetting. I fear the day when remembering is all I have.</p>

<p>I think those who suffer most in grief are the ones with the heaviest regrets. I don’t want to be one of them. If I die tomorrow, I want to be at peace with how I lived. I want to know that I loved fully, gave freely, and didn’t wait for later to be the person I was meant to be for the people I care about.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve always been an emotional person. Someone who’s deeply sentimental, easily moved by small gestures, old photos, and fading memories. Thankfully, I never had to face real loss when I was young. But as I grow older, the thought of grief feels like a shadow that creeps closer with each passing year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Being Held Captive by My Emotions</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/On-Being-Held-Captive-By-My-Emotions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Being Held Captive by My Emotions" /><published>2025-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/On-Being-Held-Captive-By-My-Emotions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/On-Being-Held-Captive-By-My-Emotions/"><![CDATA[<p>Growing up, I was always held captive by my emotions. I had no real control over my impulses. I would get angry and say things recklessly, often hurting the people I loved. It was like when something triggers you and you feel that tingling in the back of your neck. You try to bite your tongue because you know nothing good will come out. A wave of rage passes over you and you black out. Before you know it, you are lashing out verbally and physically. It feels sinfully good to release that pent-up tension. But once the adrenaline fades, guilt rushes in. You reflect on your outburst and realize the problem was never as big as your reaction. That was my reality.</p>

<p>I would also fall into depression for days, making reckless decisions to feel better. I was often erratic. Unstable. I never learned how to deal with what I was feeling. I only knew how to repress it and hope it would go away. But it never did. It got worse. I felt trapped inside my own body. Miserable. Exhausted. Always stuck in fight or flight mode.</p>

<p>When you live like that for long enough, your brain stops thinking clearly. Strong emotions like anger, fear, sadness, or excitement take over. Control shifts from the part that plans and makes good decisions to the part that just reacts. The stronger the emotion, the weaker your ability to think. You stop choosing your actions. You just react.</p>

<p>It was not until recently that I learned there is a strong link between being held captive by your emotions and addiction. When you cannot manage your emotions, you look for something, anything, to escape. For me, it was a serious gambling addiction that lasted five years. I chased the high because it gave me a break from myself, from the world. I could not control my emotions and, as a result, my impulses. That is another story to share someday.</p>

<p>It took me a long time to even realize what was happening. For years, I thought my emotions and impulses were just part of who I was, something I would always be stuck with. But I am starting to see that they are not my identity. They are patterns I can, in fact, change.</p>

<p>Learning to control my emotions instead of being controlled by them is still a work in progress. And I am not going to pretend that I have it all figured out. Some days I still lose control. Some days I still chase the wrong things to avoid feeling what I need to feel. But I am starting to understand that controlling your emotions does not mean you stop feeling them. It means you stop enabling them to decide for you.</p>

<p>It is a slow, painful process. But when I remember to stay present instead of running away, I take back a little more control. I start living instead of just surviving.</p>

<p>I know I am not perfect. I still feel everything, so deeply. But I have grown to be more aware, and I am trying to stay in the driver’s seat, even if my hands are still shaking.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Growing up, I was always held captive by my emotions. I had no real control over my impulses. I would get angry and say things recklessly, often hurting the people I loved. It was like when something triggers you and you feel that tingling in the back of your neck. You try to bite your tongue because you know nothing good will come out. A wave of rage passes over you and you black out. Before you know it, you are lashing out verbally and physically. It feels sinfully good to release that pent-up tension. But once the adrenaline fades, guilt rushes in. You reflect on your outburst and realize the problem was never as big as your reaction. That was my reality.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I don’t care paradox</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/I-dont-care-paradox/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I don’t care paradox" /><published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/I-dont-care-paradox</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/I-dont-care-paradox/"><![CDATA[<p>“I don’t care.”</p>

<p>These are the three words I often say to people or mutter under my breath. You’ve probably heard them from your loved ones or friends too. They’re common, way too common. But there’s something ironic about saying them and secretly caring too much. It’s a paradox I know well. I remember repeating those words to myself over and over as a child, convincing myself that what others said didn’t matter, that their judgment was irrelevant. But the truth is,I always cared. I care way too much. I can say “I don’t care” out loud while my mind is busy dissecting all the reasons I probably should. The smallest, most trivial things stick with me. My brain takes these moments, spins them into something bigger, and suddenly they feel like they should matter. Saying “I don’t care” is easy but not really caring,  is something else entirely.</p>

<p><em>Childhood experience 1: Maybe it goes back to my childhood. I was raised by my grandmother, and whenever she was angry, she’d yell that she didn’t care if we ended up in a ditch or got kidnapped. But even then, I could tell she did care. Her constant nagging, her warnings, it was all love in disguise. I knew she cared way too much when I’d come home in the wee hours of the morning and found her waiting for me in the living room. All just to make sure I got home safely.</em></p>

<p>Over time, I started to believe that the people who say “I don’t care“ are usually the ones who care too much. I know this because I’m one of them. I overthink everything and the people around me notice. They ask if I’m okay, I shrug it off and say “I don’t care,” but inside, it eats at me. Criticism. Body language. Offhand comments. I don’t want to care, but when you grow up with such low self-esteem, no love for thyself, you naturally become a professional observer. In a way, you’re always one step ahead and you try to adjust the way you act around others so you can fit in. You constantly scan for signals, and every little thing feels like a clue confirming the worst about yourself.</p>

<p>At night, I lie in bed replaying moments like a broken recorder. I remember every time I said “I don’t care” and actually meant, “This bothers me more than it should.” Even after years of trying to condition myself to truly mean it when I say “I don’t care”, I’ve realized I’m still incapable, at least not fully.</p>

<p>Perhaps I never felt like I had the right to express how I felt. Yes, I get hurt by people’s actions or words, but I rarely speak up. Swallowing my feelings always felt easier than trying to explain them. “I don’t care” becomes a shortcut, a shield. It spares me the burden of justifying why I’m upset.</p>

<p><em>Childhood experience 2: For as long as I can remember, I was never given a chance to explain myself. Any time I tried, my family saw it as disrespect or rebellion. So I stopped. I took in all the criticism and punishment, whether I deserved it or not. I learned to stay silent. Even when it felt unfair, I shut down my emotions and endured it, because saying how I felt didn’t matter. My opinions didn’t count, I was a nobody.</em></p>

<p>At some point, I learned to deal with pain by shutting it down before anyone could notice. I avoid confrontation not because I don’t care, but because I don’t have the capacity to work through it. I never felt equipped for conversations about feelings as I didn’t build that skillset as a child. In many ways, I still process emotions with the maturity of a 7-year-old. I might sound composed on the surface, but if you asked how I felt inside, my words and feelings would contradict one another. That’s because I don’t fully understand what I’m feeling in the first place.</p>

<p>A child in this state often feels confused and overwhelmed. Like a child, I don’t have the language or tools to explain my inner world, so I shut down or withdraw. I’m afraid to say the wrong thing, unsure of whether my feelings are okay to express. Instead of reaching out, I’d rather remain in my safe zone by avoiding emotional situations altogether. Over time, this becomes a pattern: silence over honesty, distance over connection, and surface-level calm hiding inner chaos.</p>

<p>I’m learning that the words we avoid saying are often the ones we need to say the most. “I don’t care” has been my armor, but it’s also been my cage. It kept things out, but it also kept me in. Now, I’m slowly trying to unlearn that instinct, to speak up even when it feels uncomfortable, to admit when something hurts, and to let people in without needing to pretend I’m unaffected. Maybe I’ll never be someone who fully stops caring, I’m okay with it. But I can try to start by caring in the open, without shame, and that feels like a better place to start.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I don’t care.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Overcoming Perfectionism and Procrastination</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/Overcoming-perfectionism-and-procrastination/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overcoming Perfectionism and Procrastination" /><published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/Overcoming-perfectionism-and-procrastination</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/Overcoming-perfectionism-and-procrastination/"><![CDATA[<p>My boss often talks about the “get things done” mentality, a philosophy that emphasizes action over perfection. When he first introduced this concept to me, I wasn’t sure if it aligned with my values or approach to work.</p>

<p>As someone who has always been an overthinker, I’ve long aimed for perfection in everything I do. This mindset stems from my childhood, where I was constantly expected to perform at my absolute best. Over time, this pursuit of perfection led to paralysis and executive dysfunction, as the idea of tackling tasks felt overwhelming unless I could guarantee flawless results. Inevitably, procrastination and unproductivity became recurring issues in my life.</p>

<p>When my boss explained his approach, I initially resisted the idea. He encouraged me to focus on completing just one task each day, no matter how big or small, and to disregard the rest for the moment. His belief was that having a tangible deliverable by the end of the day meant I was being efficient. At first, I thought this was counterproductive; why settle for mediocrity when I could strive for excellence?</p>

<p>However, as time passed, his ideology began to resonate with me. I started noticing how much time I wasted obsessing over perfecting my work. Instead of making progress, I often felt stuck and overwhelmed, leaving me with nothing accomplished by the end of the day. This not only made me feel incompetent but also left me frustrated with myself for wasting valuable time and energy.</p>

<p>The concept became even clearer when my boss sent me to a training program where I encountered Paul Graham’s essay, <em>Startups in 13 Sentences</em>. While Graham’s advice is tailored to startups, I realized its principles could easily be applied to everyday life and productivity. Two lines from his essay stood out to me:</p>

<p>Launch fast. Let your idea evolve.</p>

<p>These statements encapsulate the essence of taking action without waiting for perfect conditions or overthinking every detail. They emphasize starting somewhere or anywhere, allowing clarity and momentum to build as you move forward. The first step doesn’t need to be flawless; it simply needs to be taken. From there, you can refine your efforts based on what you learn along the way. True progress often comes from adaptability rather than rigidly adhering to an original plan.</p>

<p>While I’m still working on fully integrating this mindset into my daily life, it has already helped me overcome procrastination and deliver results, even if they’re small steps forward. By focusing on action rather than perfection, I’ve started breaking free from the cycle of paralysis and have found a new sense of productivity and purpose.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My boss often talks about the “get things done” mentality, a philosophy that emphasizes action over perfection. When he first introduced this concept to me, I wasn’t sure if it aligned with my values or approach to work.]]></summary></entry></feed>