<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://hofeiying.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://hofeiying.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-29T03:50:24+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Home</title><subtitle>Product Leader.</subtitle><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">The Truth Will Set You Free</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/The-Truth-Will-Set-You-Free/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Truth Will Set You Free" /><published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/The-Truth-Will-Set-You-Free</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/The-Truth-Will-Set-You-Free/"><![CDATA[<p>The value of honesty was instilled in me throughout childhood, not just at home but also in classrooms and by figures of authority. Growing up, it was common to hear elders stress the importance of truthfulness. However, honesty wasn’t always simple.</p>

<p>My father was intimidating, and even now, memories of his anger unsettle me. Despite this fear, as a child, I often found myself in trouble. Teachers would call home to report my misbehavior, and inevitably, my father would be waiting, cane in hand. He would stare deeply into my eyes, asking if the accusations were true. Fearful, I’d shake my head, nervously stuttering, “No.”</p>

<p>Even when I thought I’d delivered my most convincing lie, he saw right through it. Each time he caught me lying, he would say firmly, “I hate it when you lie. Look at me and tell me the truth, or you’ll face the consequence.”</p>

<p>So, I adapted. I started telling the truth, believing honesty would grant me leniency. But I was mistaken. Even when truthful, particularly when wrongly accused or misunderstood, I faced punishment just as severe. This harsh reality taught me a painful lesson: honesty doesn’t always protect you from criticism or consequence.</p>

<p>The abusive repercussions of lying to my father had a profound impact. Because he always saw through my deceit, I became convinced that I was simply born to be terrible at lying. Subconsciously, this belief lingered, making lying extraordinarily difficult for me when growing up. Ironically, as I grew older, the fear of hurting others became greater than the fear of getting caught in a lie. Lying eventually became less frightening than allowing those I loved to see the truth about me.</p>

<p>Whenever confronted with admitting my truth, I felt compelled to bend the truth or outright lie. My dishonesty never arose from malicious intent, nor was it ever employed to harm others. Instead, my lies were always about concealing my own wrongdoings. It was always done to protect myself and others. I’d rather carry my burdens alone, despite the mental toll, believing I was sparing those I love from disappointment and shame at discovering just how flawed I truly am.</p>

<p>Each lie told became increasingly harder to manage, for lies inevitably require more lies to sustain them. Over time it gets harder and harder to catch up with them because they’re always made up on the spur of the moment when panic sets in.</p>

<p>“No man has a good enough memory to be a good liar.”</p>

<p>The guilt from lying and the shame of feeling like you’ve failed everyone, including yourself, gnaws at you relentlessly. The constant dread that your lies coming to light is exhausting, like dragging a heavy weight you cannot release till the truth is finally told.</p>

<p>Being self-aware amplifies the agony of lying; the strain on your conscience is immense. Sometimes I wish I was oblivious to the discomfort of deceit. Maybe I wouldn’t be constantly haunted by the guilt that follows.</p>

<p>Lying, in those moments, always felt like a non-negotiable option. You craft false narratives, construct versions of yourself you wish were true. If you must be judged for your mistakes, you prefer it to be perceived as something “less” severe than the reality, because in those brief moments, lying offers temporary relief and makes you feel better. Even though you know it’s wrong..</p>

<p>But here’s an undeniable truth: Lies always surface eventually. And when they do, the erosion of trust cuts deeper than any temporary discomfort honesty might have caused initially. Consider the scenario where your truth might cause no immediate harm to your loved ones, but being caught in a lie or multiple lies later would inflict deeper pain. It creates a barrier for trust. I’ve always known this from the moment I learnt to bury uncomfortable truths. Despite that, whenever I faced such situations, I still instinctively believe that my lies are acts of mercy on myself and the people who I love. Unfortunately, It’s a delusion that only the insecure would buy.</p>

<p>Having said so much, I doubt I was able to encapsulate the true complexity and emotional toll of lying. But one thing is certain: the truth, however painful, will set you free, even if it feels utterly unbearable in the moment. Telling the truth is also a form of acceptance and a sign that you are ready for growth. Am I Ready?</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The value of honesty was instilled in me throughout childhood, not just at home but also in classrooms and by figures of authority. Growing up, it was common to hear elders stress the importance of truthfulness. However, honesty wasn’t always simple.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Mirage of Greener Grass</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/The-Mirage-of-Greener-Grass/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Mirage of Greener Grass" /><published>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/The-Mirage-of-Greener-Grass</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/The-Mirage-of-Greener-Grass/"><![CDATA[<p>I grew up under the shadow of an abusive and controlling father. My childhood felt like being a bird trapped in a cage, constantly yearning for the sky that was always just beyond my reach. Every daydream revolved around the moment I’d finally gather the courage to break free from his grip and experience life on my own terms. I genuinely believed that freedom was the missing piece, the ultimate goal that would finally make life complete. For that freedom, I was willing to pay any price.</p>

<p>Eventually, I found the strength to reclaim my life. I took the leap and fought hard for the freedom I’d longed for. Yet, to my dismay, happiness eluded me. Over the years, the stress and emotional turmoil led me to gain 20 kilograms, as I resorted to binge eating to cope. The weight gain amplified my insecurities, fueling self-loathing and sadness. It might seem trivial to some, but the agony of body dysmorphia is something only those who’ve experienced it, can truly grasp. Again, I convinced myself: if only I could achieve an athlete’s physique, then surely contentment would follow, even if it meant sacrificing some of that hard-earned freedom.</p>

<p>And so, determined, I pushed forward, disciplined myself, and successfully got into shape. Finally, I had both the freedom and the physique others admired. But even then, true peace remained elusive. University began, and with it came overwhelming anxiety about the uncertainty of my future. To escape this anxiety, I fell into another trap,addiction, which quickly led to mounting debt. Life felt like an endless cycle of misery, pulling me back into the same trap. I thought again: if only I were debt-free, then surely I’d find happiness.</p>

<p>But here’s the truth I’ve come to painfully realize: the grass always appears greener until it isn’t. Even if my debt vanished overnight at the cost of my freedom or my health, dissatisfaction would inevitably linger. Real happiness doesn’t spring from external circumstances or the resolution of temporary hardships. True contentment must be cultivated deep within ourselves, nurtured through gratitude and a sincere appreciation for life’s small yet meaningful milestones. Constantly chasing after more only leaves us perpetually empty.</p>

<p>Greed, after all, is a sin,not merely because it makes us endlessly desire more, but because it blinds us to the beauty and abundance we already possess.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I grew up under the shadow of an abusive and controlling father. My childhood felt like being a bird trapped in a cage, constantly yearning for the sky that was always just beyond my reach. Every daydream revolved around the moment I’d finally gather the courage to break free from his grip and experience life on my own terms. I genuinely believed that freedom was the missing piece, the ultimate goal that would finally make life complete. For that freedom, I was willing to pay any price.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Life Spent On Self-Sabotage</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/A-Life-Spent-On-Self-Sabotage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Life Spent On Self-Sabotage" /><published>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/A-Life-Spent-On-Self-Sabotage</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/A-Life-Spent-On-Self-Sabotage/"><![CDATA[<p>I always assumed that the older I got, the closer I’d be to the peace I desperately yearned for as a child. The truth is, peace was never something I could reliably expect. Conflict felt more certain than winning the lottery. If you asked me to name a moment from my childhood when I genuinely felt safe or at ease, I’m not sure I could. Each time I dared to catch my breath, another storm was already brewing on the horizon.</p>

<p>At some point, I stopped believing I deserve a simple, peaceful life. My childhood memories became filled with endless loops of tension and turmoil. There was always a feeling of judgment day looming, a heavy, unsettling sensation that prevented me from ever truly feeling like I don’t constantly have weights on my shoulders.</p>

<p>These experiences, imprinted so early, eventually turned peace itself into something frightening, even dangerous. When calm arrived, I’d instinctively brace myself for disaster. Silence didn’t soothe me; it triggered anxiety. Instead of savoring these tranquil moments, I spent them anticipating their inevitable demise. This anxiety was so profound that I couldn’t allow myself to trust in moments of genuine calm. How could I if all I’ve ever known was chaos?</p>

<p>And so began my habit of self-sabotage—a quiet war against my own happiness. I subconsciously learned to disrupt the peace by myself before something else could destroy it. Over time, my body and mind developed an involuntary reflex to push away tranquility. Happiness felt too vulnerable, too uncertain, and too good to be real. Sabotaging myself became my way of maintaining control; if the chaos was self-inflicted, at least it was predictable.</p>

<p>These acts of self-sabotage have inflicted tremendous pains on my healing. It doesn’t help being so aware of myself yet having no way to prevent these habits from reoccurring.  But I want it to stop. I need it to stop.</p>

<p>Looking back clearly at the patterns I’ve carried with me, I’ve begun to wonder if perhaps the bravest thing I could do is to stop fighting against myself. Maybe the real challenge isn’t surviving chaos, but allowing myself the bravery of embracing calm without conditions or skepticism. Perhaps the most powerful rebellion against a painful past isn’t more struggle, but learning how to rest in moments of genuine ease without fearing their end.</p>

<p>I’m slowly realizing that peace doesn’t have to be a fragile, nor a temporary gift; it’s not something reserved for those who’ve earned it through endless suffering. Peace is steady, patient, and always available beneath life’s turbulence, just like a river gently flowing, ready for me to finally trust it enough to let myself drift along its current, without constantly looking ahead for rapids. If I learn to simply embrace the imperfections of life by just being at peace, there wouldn’t be a need for self-sabotage.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I always assumed that the older I got, the closer I’d be to the peace I desperately yearned for as a child. The truth is, peace was never something I could reliably expect. Conflict felt more certain than winning the lottery. If you asked me to name a moment from my childhood when I genuinely felt safe or at ease, I’m not sure I could. Each time I dared to catch my breath, another storm was already brewing on the horizon.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Edge of Grief</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/The-Edge-of-Grief/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Edge of Grief" /><published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/The-Edge-of-Grief</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/The-Edge-of-Grief/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve always been an emotional person. Someone who’s deeply sentimental, easily moved by small gestures, old photos, and fading memories. Thankfully, I never had to face real loss when I was young. But as I grow older, the thought of grief feels like a shadow that creeps closer with each passing year.</p>

<p>There have been moments where I’ve spiraled into panic attacks, triggered by obsessive thoughts of losing the people I love. These imagined tragedies loop in my mind like a broken record. I know they’re not real, but when they take over, logic disappears. I begin to grieve events that haven’t happened. It feels real and I grieve for a situation that doesn’t exist. And the fear becomes overwhelming: What if one day someone I love is just… gone? How would I survive that?</p>

<p>Not long ago, someone close to me passed away. A friend, but more than that, a steady older brother presence in my life. Someone who looked out for me when I didn’t know I needed looking after. His death came without warning, so sudden and sharp. It cracked something open in me, forcing questions I had been avoiding to surface again.</p>

<p>What is this life? What does it mean to be here, only to vanish? Why does everything feel so temporary, so brittle, so easily lost?</p>

<p>If I could choose my fate, I think I’d rather leave this world before my loved ones. It might sound selfish, but I’d rather be spared the pain of loss than endure the silence that follows it. The truth is harsh: when someone dies, they’re truly gone. People say memories live on, but even they will begin to blur someday. Eventually, the voice you once heard clearly becomes an echo. Photos become symbols. You see, death steals more than just people, it steals the feeling of them.</p>

<p>Everything in life is ephemeral. It is fragile. It can change overnight.</p>

<p>And maybe the only way to cope with this inevitable truth is to stay grounded in the present. To fully appreciate the people I love while they are still here. To be more intentional with my time. More generous with my love. More present in my conversations. I have begun taking more photos, capturing the ordinary, a shared laugh, a quiet meal, a hand held a little longer, because I fear forgetting. I fear the day when remembering is all I have.</p>

<p>I think those who suffer most in grief are the ones with the heaviest regrets. I don’t want to be one of them. If I die tomorrow, I want to be at peace with how I lived. I want to know that I loved fully, gave freely, and didn’t wait for later to be the person I was meant to be for the people I care about.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve always been an emotional person. Someone who’s deeply sentimental, easily moved by small gestures, old photos, and fading memories. Thankfully, I never had to face real loss when I was young. But as I grow older, the thought of grief feels like a shadow that creeps closer with each passing year.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Being Held Captive by My Emotions</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/On-Being-Held-Captive-By-My-Emotions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Being Held Captive by My Emotions" /><published>2025-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/On-Being-Held-Captive-By-My-Emotions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/On-Being-Held-Captive-By-My-Emotions/"><![CDATA[<p>Growing up, I was always held captive by my emotions. I had no real control over my impulses. I would get angry and say things recklessly, often hurting the people I loved. It was like when something triggers you and you feel that tingling in the back of your neck. You try to bite your tongue because you know nothing good will come out. A wave of rage passes over you and you black out. Before you know it, you are lashing out verbally and physically. It feels sinfully good to release that pent-up tension. But once the adrenaline fades, guilt rushes in. You reflect on your outburst and realize the problem was never as big as your reaction. That was my reality.</p>

<p>I would also fall into depression for days, making reckless decisions to feel better. I was often erratic. Unstable. I never learned how to deal with what I was feeling. I only knew how to repress it and hope it would go away. But it never did. It got worse. I felt trapped inside my own body. Miserable. Exhausted. Always stuck in fight or flight mode.</p>

<p>When you live like that for long enough, your brain stops thinking clearly. Strong emotions like anger, fear, sadness, or excitement take over. Control shifts from the part that plans and makes good decisions to the part that just reacts. The stronger the emotion, the weaker your ability to think. You stop choosing your actions. You just react.</p>

<p>It was not until recently that I learned there is a strong link between being held captive by your emotions and addiction. When you cannot manage your emotions, you look for something, anything, to escape. For me, it was a serious gambling addiction that lasted five years. I chased the high because it gave me a break from myself, from the world. I could not control my emotions and, as a result, my impulses. That is another story to share someday.</p>

<p>It took me a long time to even realize what was happening. For years, I thought my emotions and impulses were just part of who I was, something I would always be stuck with. But I am starting to see that they are not my identity. They are patterns I can, in fact, change.</p>

<p>Learning to control my emotions instead of being controlled by them is still a work in progress. And I am not going to pretend that I have it all figured out. Some days I still lose control. Some days I still chase the wrong things to avoid feeling what I need to feel. But I am starting to understand that controlling your emotions does not mean you stop feeling them. It means you stop enabling them to decide for you.</p>

<p>It is a slow, painful process. But when I remember to stay present instead of running away, I take back a little more control. I start living instead of just surviving.</p>

<p>I know I am not perfect. I still feel everything, so deeply. But I have grown to be more aware, and I am trying to stay in the driver’s seat, even if my hands are still shaking.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Growing up, I was always held captive by my emotions. I had no real control over my impulses. I would get angry and say things recklessly, often hurting the people I loved. It was like when something triggers you and you feel that tingling in the back of your neck. You try to bite your tongue because you know nothing good will come out. A wave of rage passes over you and you black out. Before you know it, you are lashing out verbally and physically. It feels sinfully good to release that pent-up tension. But once the adrenaline fades, guilt rushes in. You reflect on your outburst and realize the problem was never as big as your reaction. That was my reality.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I don’t care paradox</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/I-dont-care-paradox/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I don’t care paradox" /><published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/I-dont-care-paradox</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/I-dont-care-paradox/"><![CDATA[<p>“I don’t care.”</p>

<p>These are the three words I often say to people or mutter under my breath. You’ve probably heard them from your loved ones or friends too. They’re common, way too common. But there’s something ironic about saying them and secretly caring too much. It’s a paradox I know well. I remember repeating those words to myself over and over as a child, convincing myself that what others said didn’t matter, that their judgment was irrelevant. But the truth is,I always cared. I care way too much. I can say “I don’t care” out loud while my mind is busy dissecting all the reasons I probably should. The smallest, most trivial things stick with me. My brain takes these moments, spins them into something bigger, and suddenly they feel like they should matter. Saying “I don’t care” is easy but not really caring,  is something else entirely.</p>

<p><em>Childhood experience 1: Maybe it goes back to my childhood. I was raised by my grandmother, and whenever she was angry, she’d yell that she didn’t care if we ended up in a ditch or got kidnapped. But even then, I could tell she did care. Her constant nagging, her warnings, it was all love in disguise. I knew she cared way too much when I’d come home in the wee hours of the morning and found her waiting for me in the living room. All just to make sure I got home safely.</em></p>

<p>Over time, I started to believe that the people who say “I don’t care“ are usually the ones who care too much. I know this because I’m one of them. I overthink everything and the people around me notice. They ask if I’m okay, I shrug it off and say “I don’t care,” but inside, it eats at me. Criticism. Body language. Offhand comments. I don’t want to care, but when you grow up with such low self-esteem, no love for thyself, you naturally become a professional observer. In a way, you’re always one step ahead and you try to adjust the way you act around others so you can fit in. You constantly scan for signals, and every little thing feels like a clue confirming the worst about yourself.</p>

<p>At night, I lie in bed replaying moments like a broken recorder. I remember every time I said “I don’t care” and actually meant, “This bothers me more than it should.” Even after years of trying to condition myself to truly mean it when I say “I don’t care”, I’ve realized I’m still incapable, at least not fully.</p>

<p>Perhaps I never felt like I had the right to express how I felt. Yes, I get hurt by people’s actions or words, but I rarely speak up. Swallowing my feelings always felt easier than trying to explain them. “I don’t care” becomes a shortcut, a shield. It spares me the burden of justifying why I’m upset.</p>

<p><em>Childhood experience 2: For as long as I can remember, I was never given a chance to explain myself. Any time I tried, my family saw it as disrespect or rebellion. So I stopped. I took in all the criticism and punishment, whether I deserved it or not. I learned to stay silent. Even when it felt unfair, I shut down my emotions and endured it, because saying how I felt didn’t matter. My opinions didn’t count, I was a nobody.</em></p>

<p>At some point, I learned to deal with pain by shutting it down before anyone could notice. I avoid confrontation not because I don’t care, but because I don’t have the capacity to work through it. I never felt equipped for conversations about feelings as I didn’t build that skillset as a child. In many ways, I still process emotions with the maturity of a 7-year-old. I might sound composed on the surface, but if you asked how I felt inside, my words and feelings would contradict one another. That’s because I don’t fully understand what I’m feeling in the first place.</p>

<p>A child in this state often feels confused and overwhelmed. Like a child, I don’t have the language or tools to explain my inner world, so I shut down or withdraw. I’m afraid to say the wrong thing, unsure of whether my feelings are okay to express. Instead of reaching out, I’d rather remain in my safe zone by avoiding emotional situations altogether. Over time, this becomes a pattern: silence over honesty, distance over connection, and surface-level calm hiding inner chaos.</p>

<p>I’m learning that the words we avoid saying are often the ones we need to say the most. “I don’t care” has been my armor, but it’s also been my cage. It kept things out, but it also kept me in. Now, I’m slowly trying to unlearn that instinct, to speak up even when it feels uncomfortable, to admit when something hurts, and to let people in without needing to pretend I’m unaffected. Maybe I’ll never be someone who fully stops caring, I’m okay with it. But I can try to start by caring in the open, without shame, and that feels like a better place to start.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I don’t care.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Overcoming Perfectionism and Procrastination</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/Overcoming-perfectionism-and-procrastination/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overcoming Perfectionism and Procrastination" /><published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/Overcoming-perfectionism-and-procrastination</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/Overcoming-perfectionism-and-procrastination/"><![CDATA[<p>My boss often talks about the “get things done” mentality, a philosophy that emphasizes action over perfection. When he first introduced this concept to me, I wasn’t sure if it aligned with my values or approach to work.</p>

<p>As someone who has always been an overthinker, I’ve long aimed for perfection in everything I do. This mindset stems from my childhood, where I was constantly expected to perform at my absolute best. Over time, this pursuit of perfection led to paralysis and executive dysfunction, as the idea of tackling tasks felt overwhelming unless I could guarantee flawless results. Inevitably, procrastination and unproductivity became recurring issues in my life.</p>

<p>When my boss explained his approach, I initially resisted the idea. He encouraged me to focus on completing just one task each day, no matter how big or small, and to disregard the rest for the moment. His belief was that having a tangible deliverable by the end of the day meant I was being efficient. At first, I thought this was counterproductive; why settle for mediocrity when I could strive for excellence?</p>

<p>However, as time passed, his ideology began to resonate with me. I started noticing how much time I wasted obsessing over perfecting my work. Instead of making progress, I often felt stuck and overwhelmed, leaving me with nothing accomplished by the end of the day. This not only made me feel incompetent but also left me frustrated with myself for wasting valuable time and energy.</p>

<p>The concept became even clearer when my boss sent me to a training program where I encountered Paul Graham’s essay, <em>Startups in 13 Sentences</em>. While Graham’s advice is tailored to startups, I realized its principles could easily be applied to everyday life and productivity. Two lines from his essay stood out to me:</p>

<p>Launch fast. Let your idea evolve.</p>

<p>These statements encapsulate the essence of taking action without waiting for perfect conditions or overthinking every detail. They emphasize starting somewhere or anywhere, allowing clarity and momentum to build as you move forward. The first step doesn’t need to be flawless; it simply needs to be taken. From there, you can refine your efforts based on what you learn along the way. True progress often comes from adaptability rather than rigidly adhering to an original plan.</p>

<p>While I’m still working on fully integrating this mindset into my daily life, it has already helped me overcome procrastination and deliver results, even if they’re small steps forward. By focusing on action rather than perfection, I’ve started breaking free from the cycle of paralysis and have found a new sense of productivity and purpose.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My boss often talks about the “get things done” mentality, a philosophy that emphasizes action over perfection. When he first introduced this concept to me, I wasn’t sure if it aligned with my values or approach to work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is The Meaning of Life</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/What-is-the-meaning-of-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is The Meaning of Life" /><published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/What-is-the-meaning-of-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/What-is-the-meaning-of-life/"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since I was a child, I’ve carried with me a restless curiosity about the world. It stayed with me through my teenage years and now into adulthood. I’ve always been drawn to solving the questions that intrigues me. But one question in particular still lingers unanswered: What is the meaning of my existence?</p>

<p>Everyone around me seems to be finding their way. As they grow older, their paths become clearer. Careers take shape, passions deepen, and life begins to settle into rhythm. But for me, it’s the opposite. I remember wanting to be a pop star, a music producer, an astronaut, an entrepreneur etc. My dreams as a child were bold, even if they didn’t align with the other kids around me. But as I grow older, those dreams begin to fade, like fog dissolving under sunlight.</p>

<p>In what felt like a blink of an eye, I am now 24. Having lost those ambitions along the way, I don’t know what excites me anymore. I don’t know why I’m here. The more I try to chase purpose, the more it slips away. It feels like falling into a rabbit hole of questions, each one leading further from clarity. The harder I search, the further I drift from meaning and it feels like I’m losing my mind.</p>

<p>Growing up in a dysfunctional family gave me a strong urge to succeed. As a young girl, I promised myself that when I got older, I would escape and rewrite my story. I always believed I was meant to be different. That I was meant to stand out. To change the world, make something of myself. I’d lay in bed at night making promises to myself, convinced that someday I’d look back to this period in my life and say I made it. But now, as I’m writing this, I don’t know what to tell the younger version of me. I haven’t kept the promises I made to her, and that fills me with excruciating shame.</p>

<p>This feeling of being lost, of not measuring up, has drained life of all its color. Some nights I lie awake wondering: What’s the point of it all? Why was I brought into this world just to decay when time runs out? At times I even toy with the idea that maybe none of this is real. Maybe we’re in a simulation, like The Matrix. And if that’s true, I would be the main character and I should be able to choose how this life unfolds for me.</p>

<p>But even then, I’m back to the same question: what is my purpose? How can I become the person my younger self believed I would be, when I no longer know who I am…</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever since I was a child, I’ve carried with me a restless curiosity about the world. It stayed with me through my teenage years and now into adulthood. I’ve always been drawn to solving the questions that intrigues me. But one question in particular still lingers unanswered: What is the meaning of my existence?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conditioned Silence</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/Conditioned-Silence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conditioned Silence" /><published>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/Conditioned-Silence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/Conditioned-Silence/"><![CDATA[<p>Part of growing up is learning who you really are. For me, that process has been painful.</p>

<p>I come from a dysfunctional family where I had to manage my emotions alone from a young age. Over time, I learned to repress them. I believed I wasn’t allowed to feel what I felt. I never tried to explain or justify what I was going through because I always felt powerless. I was conditioned to believe I was beneath everyone else. My self-worth was constantly under attack and I struggled to form meaningful connections, whether with friends or romantic partners. It started at home, where I was criticized simply for existing. I could name countless ways I was mistreated by my family, but revisiting those memories only brings pain. What I’m trying to do through journaling, is process that trauma and heal from the things I didn’t deserve to go through as a child.</p>

<p>Home has never felt like a place where I could share my burdens. It was where the burdens were created. When I looked for relief at school, I couldn’t open up there either. I’d show up to class with invisible wounds and sometimes visible ones. Leaving home always felt safer than staying, but the fear never left me. I found it hard to confide in anyone because I was afraid they would despise me like my own family did.</p>

<p>It felt like I was being trained through punishment, conditioned the same way Pavlov trained his dogs. In his experiment, Pavlov rang a bell before feeding them. Eventually, the sound alone made them salivate, even when no food came. They had learned to associate a stimulus with an automatic response. That was me. Every time I cried or showed emotion, my father punished me. The more pain I expressed, the harsher the reaction. I was conditioned to believe that emotions led to violence. So I stopped crying. I stopped showing how I felt. My nervous system learned that feeling was dangerous and vulnerability meant pain.</p>

<p>I don’t remember exactly when, but I learned early on to cope by hiding my emotions. Even with “close friends”, I kept everything bottled up. I let people mistreat me because I thought having a few “friends” was better than being alone. I also became hyper-aware of other people’s emotions, constantly observing and adjusting to avoid conflict. I’m always walking on eggshells. I was terrified of being rejected again, the way my family had rejected me. So I stayed quiet, even when I was being used. As an adult, I now recognize that I developed people-pleasing habits as a coping mechanism and they still show up in me today.</p>

<p>I never really shared what was going on at home or showed anyone who I truly was. I was scared that if they saw the real me, they’d walk away. So I built an armor around my heart. If someone rejected me, at least I could say they didn’t reject the real me, but the version I created for them to see. That armor made it nearly impossible to let anyone in and when people got too close, I felt suffocated. I would find ways to push them away because I believed that if someone truly knew me, they would abandon me. Attempting to leave first always gave me a sense of control. Rejecting people was better than being rejected myself.</p>

<p>Sometimes, there’s nothing I want or need more than connection. But I’ve lived my whole life this way, always hiding behind a facade. It’s hard to imagine a day where I am truly nonchalant about the way people view me and allow myself to be just, me. Or perhaps it’s better to keep my distance from emotions, people, after all. Maybe that’s the only way to protect my sanity and what’s left of my shattered soul from another heartache.</p>

<p>I wish someone could live in my head for a day and understand how painfully ironic it is to feel everything and nothing all at once. But i wouldn’t wish this pain on my enemies either haha.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Part of growing up is learning who you really are. For me, that process has been painful.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A letter to the person who’ve hurt me the most</title><link href="https://hofeiying.com/Dear-Dad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A letter to the person who’ve hurt me the most" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://hofeiying.com/Dear-Dad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://hofeiying.com/Dear-Dad/"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Dad,</p>

<p>It’s your birthday today, and it’s been a long time since I celebrated it with you. I don’t have the courage to send this letter because deep down I think you’re still the same person and wouldn’t react well. I remember when I was a kid, I stopped writing you birthday letters after you tore up the card I made for you one year. You laughed and told me to spend my time studying instead. That’s okay. I just need to release what’s built up inside me, so here goes…</p>

<p>A part of me knows you love me, but another part struggles to believe it. I recognize our relationship wasn’t entirely bad, yet I can’t seem to remember the good moments. Whenever I try to recall when you were truly a father to me, it’s as if the memories escape me. Perhaps I’ve repressed the good moments, overshadowed by the weight of the bad ones.</p>

<p>When I was 7, you made me watch you punish my older sister. That memory still haunts me. I feared if I ever fell short of your expectations, you’d put me through the same pain all because she didn’t get straight A’s. Little did I know this foreshadowed the start of my nightmare.</p>

<p>When I was 8, you caught me lying about my tuition homework. You stormed into my room, said I didn’t deserve to look pretty, and cut my hair off with scissors. That was the first time I experienced your frightening side myself. From then on, I believed I had no right to feel beautiful if I failed your standards.</p>

<p>When I was 9, my teacher called you about an incomplete assignment. I came home shivering in fear, knowing you’d follow through on every threat. I prayed desperately in the altar room, hoping you’d show mercy to a little girl. Within minutes of arriving home, you took out the cane, whipped me in anger, dragged me toward the stairs, and tried pushing me down. I ran out of the house covered in bruises, fearing for my life. I vividly remember the humiliation as neighbors drove past in shock.</p>

<p>When I was 10, you caught me opening the safe. Instead of explaining its seriousness, you slapped and strangled me, then beat me with the cane. I held back tears, terrified they’d trigger more punishment.</p>

<p>When I was 11, we were eating lunch together. You criticized how I looked and ate, threatening to throw a glass in my face. Why did you resent me so much? I was just a child, yet your words crushed every bit of confidence I had left.</p>

<p>When I was 12, my brother was born. You forbade me from interacting with him during my PSLE year. I remember watching through the window as the family enjoyed the pool, while I felt isolated and deeply outcasted. That year, I felt so badly about myself that I penned my first suicide note. Why were you so cruel?</p>

<p>When I was 13, you caught me texting boys on Instagram. You retrieved deleted messages, printed them, and showed them to our family, humiliating me deeply. You made me feel incapable of finding love, afraid you’d sabotage any happiness I sought. Even now, as an adult, relationships feel wrong, and I close myself off to the world.</p>

<p>When I was 14, you came home drunk. My younger sister simply asked you to quiet down, and you reacted violently, attacking our family. The police had to be called because you lost control. The next day, you blamed Mom for our “bad behavior,” initiating divorce without acknowledging your own mistakes. Your narcissism blinded you from seeing your faults.</p>

<p>When I was 18, I got caught sneaking out. Waking up to panicked calls, my lifelong fear of you paralyzed me. Until then, I’d lived carefully, hiding everything from you but now I was exposed. Terrified, I lied about where I was. At home, seeing you waiting, cigarette in hand, all the trauma resurfaced. Finally, something snapped. I screamed back at you, releasing years of pent up hurt. After that night, we never spoke again.</p>

<p>Dad, some people might think this isn’t a big deal. Perhaps even you wouldn’t understand how deeply your words and actions impacted me, but they affected me profoundly. You were supposed to be my protector, but because I grew up enduring your abuse, I no longer believe I deserve to be loved. You’ve shaped my struggles with trust, self worth, and relationships in ways I’m only beginning to fully understand.</p>

<p>I wish you’d been different. I wish I’d felt safe, loved, and proud around you. I wish you’d disciplined me with care instead of violence. Yet, despite the pain you’ve caused, you’ve unintentionally taught me resilience, empathy, and the importance of kindness. Because of you, I’ve discovered who I am and who I never want to be. I strive to succeed, partly to prove you wrong, but mostly to prove to myself that I’m worthy of the love and happiness you denied me. Perhaps one day, I’ll heal enough to forgive you completely, but until then, my focus is on becoming the person I needed but never had.</p>

<p>Love,
Fei</p>]]></content><author><name>Ho Fei Ying</name><email>feistyho17@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Dad,]]></summary></entry></feed>